Guide to the Parliamentary Speeches, Debates, Bills, Etc.
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Osborn fb157
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1671. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Conference with the Commons, 1671 Apr 19] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS in the hand of John
      Browne. Part of the Lord's defense of
      their right to amend bills of money.
      LJ, xii, 505.
      f.89.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT.
    - [The second address of the commissioners to King Charles II, c. late 17th century] (Box 1)
      Browne. Concerns extent and
      definition of the commissioner's
      powers.
      f.90.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT.
    - [Conference on the commission of sewers in the County of Lincoln, c. 17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      List of reasons why "the clause
      should not be confirmed for changing
      the ancient commission of sewers in
      the county of Lincoln."
      f.91.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Genealogy of Elizabeth Bates Jacob], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS, 1691 or later.
      Showing Mrs Jacob's descent and her
      previous marriage with John Browne,
      now deceased.
      f.92.
  - FOTHRINGAY COLLEGE, NORTHAMPTONSHIRE, ENGLAND.
    - [Inventory of lands and goods, c.17th century] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS. Buildings, rents,
      and tithes of Fothringay, itemized.
      f.93.
  - CARTER, EDWARD
    - [Inventory of goods and lands of a hospital for maimed soldiers, c. late 17th century] (Box 1)
      Includes assessment for support of
      hospital.
      f.94.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Ecclesiastical history of England, c.late 17th century] (Box 1)
      From Wycliffe to 1633. Notes from
      books, Parliamentary proceedings,
      and general comments on the Church
      of England.
      f.96.
  - SANDWICH, EDWARD MONTAGU, 1ST EARL OF, 1625-1672
    - [Account of the battle with the Dutch, 1665 Sept 3 & 4], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      1 p. Contemporary MS copy.Includes a list of prizes and prisoners taken. f.97.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1689. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Amendments to the Address to the King on religion and the church, 1689 Apr 15] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS. LJ, xiv, 177.
      f.98.
  - SHIPNEY, GEORGE
    - "Precedents for the Earl of Devonshire read 6 May 1689", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Precedents and statutes on the
      privileges of Parliament men. William
      Cavendish, 1st duke of Devonshire
      (1640-1707) was tried and found
      guilty of attacking Colonel Thomas
      Colepeper in 1685 by King's Bench; in
      1689 the decision was reversed, since
      the court had not allowed his plea of
      parliamentary privilege.
      f.99.
  - SHORT, DANIEL
    - [Receipt, signed 1689 Nov 21], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS; page torn.
      Payment by John Walker for John
      Browne for pictures done by Short.
      f.100.
  - BROMWICH, EDWARD
    - [ALS to John Browne, 1684/5 Jan 29], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      On parliamentary business.
      f.101.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. COURT OF KING'S BENCH.
    - [Opinion of the judges in case concerning statute for Charitable Uses, 1673 Apr 25], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      8 p.
      Concerns use of land by trustees in
      Chipping Warden, Northamptonshire.
      See f.85.
      f.102.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. COURT OF KING'S BENCH.
    - [Decision in the case between John Browne and Sir Gerrard Flettwood, 1655 July 9 & 13] (Box 1)
      4 p. 2 autograph MS, signed by Jas.Edwarde and J.Glynne (Chief Justice). A request for a new trial and the opinion of Sir John Glyn (1605-1666) and the order of the court denying the request. f.103-104.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Notes on a legal case], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Case concerns a writ of error in
      King's Bench and error in Parliament.
      f.105.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Arguments against two bills in Parliament, 1747], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Against the bills for vesting in his
      Majesty the estates of certain
      traitors and for abolishing heritable
      jurisdictions in Scotland. At the end
      of the document is a note:
      "Westminster Journals of April 2,
      1747. Quoted from a pamphlet against
      the above bills."
      f.106.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "Parliament Papers", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous scrap MS. No text. No date.
      f.107.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - "An Extract of subsidies and of the Expressions of Granting them" [c.mid-17th century] (Box 1)
      Extracts of preambles of subsidies
      from the time of Edward III to
      Philip and Mary.
      f.108.
  - COTTA, JOHN
    - [Testimony concerning death of Sir Euseby Andrews, c.17th century] (Box 1)
      Browne. This document is complete but
      was part of a larger collection of
      papers; the pages are numbered 9-12,
      and on page 9 is a poem. The
      testimony concerns a suspected case
      of poisoning.
      f.109.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Commentary on the treason laws in England, 17th century] (Box 1)
      1 p. Anonymous MS. The first page is missing. Precedents mostly from the later Middle Ages. f.109.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Genealogy of the Gardiner Family, c.1600], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Includes marriages and some birth
      dates. Most family members were "of
      London."
      f.110.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "Humble motives of assotiation to mayntaine religion established", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1601 December]
      31 p.
      Anonymous MS with corrections in the
      hand of John Browne. Two documents,
      one addressed to Queen Elizabeth, the
      other to the Archbishops and Bishops,
      urging harsher measures against
      Catholics. The author also argues
      against differentiating between
      Jesuits and other Catholics and
      claims that Puritans are being
      silenced while Papists are tolerated.
      f.111.
  - EAST INDIA COMPANY (ENGLISH)
    - [Defense of its interests in a document addressed to Parliament, 1646 Feb], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy. A defense of
      the powers of the Company and of
      joint stock.
      f.112.
  - CALCUT, JAMES
    - [Itemized list of household expenses and a receipt, signed, 1689 Dec 18] (Box 1)
      Items include candles, washing,
      claret, and a "urinall".
      Calcut was a servant of John Browne.
      f.113.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Extracts from a book on Oliver Cromwell, late 17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      f.114.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. NAVY.
    - "A List of the Ships belonging to His Majesties Navy-Royal", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1666]
      Printed in London.
      Lists names of ships, and number of
      men and guns on each ship.
      f.115.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Genealogy of the Radcliffe family, 1647 or later], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Descent of the Earls of Sussex from
      the Normans. Edward Radcliffe, 6th
      Earl of Sussex (1559-1643) died in
      1643 without issue, and there were
      disputes among his heirs over his
      titles. GEC Peerage, v.12, 530.
      f.116.